RAVI PARMAR

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

| C | O | N | Т | Α | C | Τ |
|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|
| | | | | | | |

| +919664523267 |
|---------------|
| |

ravi.parmar1206@gmail.com



Ahemdabad, Gujarat, India



https://www.linkedin.com/in/r avi-parmar207257166

TECNICAL SKILLS

.Net 6, .Net 5, .Net core 3.1, ASP.NET MVC, WEB API WEB API CORE, Asp.net C# .NET LINQ, Microsoft Azure Fundamental, Azure Mail service, Web Jobs, CI/CD, MS SQL Server, iQuery, JavaScript Bootstrap ,HTML,/HTML5, CSS/CSS3 IIS, Microservices, 3 tier architecture, Solid principle, Software Design patterns.

ROLE AND RESPONSIBILITY

Develop software solutions by following the software development lifecycle, determining operational feasibility, documenting and demonstrating solutions, and preparing and installing solutions. Developing software our users need, mentor junior and mid-level engineers collaborate with team to brainstorm and create new products grow engineering teams by make informed decisions quickly and taking ownership of services and applications at scale work collaboratively with others to achieve goals. Be a persistent, creative problem -solver. Stay on the leading edge of development practices and understand business needs and know how to create the tools to manage them.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Application

Dharamsinh Desai Institute Of Technology University

2009-2012

Master in science (information technology)

Charusat University

2012-2014

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Simforms Solution LLP 06/2022 - present

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

TechnoBrains Business Solution LLP 09/2021 - 06/2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Paperchase software solution pvt ltd 12-2014 - 07 - 2021

PROFILE

Highly skilled and motivated senior software developer having experience of 8 years in analysis, design, development of various internet based application and exceptional problem solver with creative abilities. Good experience in development of application in .Net 6, .Net 5, .Net core 3.1, ASP.NET MVC, 3rd party integrations etc. Leader with excellent interpersonal skills and motivational abilities to develop collaborative relationships among high functioning teams. Strong communication skills with result oriented and passion to learn and explore new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Paperchase software solution pvt ltd

2014 - 2021

- Project Title: TIME TRACKER is an accurate time tracking and time management software, it helps you know if your team is productive and individuals, Client Detail, Login Detail, Holiday Details and many more. It is a webbased solution that provides time tracking, computer work session monitoring, reminder, excel doc file, Invoicing reporting tools, integration. Furthermore, it contains multiple internal company modules in an application such as Review System, Download Tracker, Task Tracker, ACS Report, Phone Book and many more
- Project Title: Rota Online has been developed aim to handled Restaurant staff scheduling. The things that we find valuable our clients, being able to see staff availability and most importantly the daily reminders - so none of our staff have any excuse for not knowing when their next shift is. And displaying reports as per Rota such as Rota summary report, Rota actual reports and many more.

TechnoBrains Business Solution LLP

2021-2022

Sr. Software Engineer

- STQ Supply Traq
- OTQ Onco Trag
- GTQ Gene Traq

All applications shows the pharmaceutical company data. It is web based solution that display data in power-bi chart and use multiple Microsoft Azure service such as AzureB2C, AzureActiveDirectory and many more

Sr. Software Engineer

Simforms Solution LLP

2022 - Present

Project Title: 3 Birds Marketing is uniquely positioned to blend online data (Email, Clicks, Page Sessions, Appointments, Leads) with offline data (Sales, Service) to deliver the most robust and hyper personalized automotive lifecycle management solution in the industry.